### Liam McIsaac



# liamskimac@gmail.com 07925 897041 Nelson Cottage, Mundford, UK www.linkedin.com/in/liam-biam-se

I am a friendly, enthusiastic and highly motivated person who has developed a wide variety of skills through my education, life experiences, and employment. Having taught science, maths, and English in the UK and abroad for eight years, I have decided to change careers to continue my professional progression, and follow a path that will enable me to further contribute to the changes in society that I want to see. With coding, what started as a hobby has become something I am devoted to - exploring opportunities, improving my skills and knowledge, and challenging myself. My diverse employment in education has been such a rewarding and exciting career, and my philosophy of inspiration and excitement will continue into the next stage of my career. From teaching to volunteering, I am always determined to help others, and I have recognised the potential of technology as a key to developing a sustainable world for all - something that I want to be a part of.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Software Engineer Bootcamp** 

HyperionDev

December 2022 - Present

- Software development in Python and SQL experience in Django and SQLite
- Using the power of object-oriented programming modelling a system as a collection of objects
- Utilising data science libraries to develop data-driven web applications
- Natural language programming, systems analysis, systems design
- Management of the software development life cycle
- Static, dynamic, and backend web development experience in CSS, HTML, and Bootstrap
- Source version control, Git, Network Protocols, Systems Architecture, Databases

**Science Tutor** 

Breckland School, Brandon, Suffolk

January 2022 - July 2022

• Tutoring science from year 7 to 11 - ranging from GCSE exam preparation and teaching catch-up GCSE science, re-engaging students with science by exploring interesting topics and experiments

**Teacher of Science** 

St Paul's Junior School, Barnes, London

January 2021 - January 2022

 Responsibilities: leading science club, tutoring a Year 8 form, attending parent's evenings, writing reports, providing regular pupil feedback, contributing to the scheme of work, collaborating with science colleagues, working across school regarding pastoral, behavioural, and safeguarding issues

Science and English Teacher

BlingABC and Freelance

September 2019 - January 2021

 Teaching and tutoring Science and English to students aged 7-18, using dedicated online platforms to engage my students and ensure success. Creating exciting one-to-one and group lessons using a range of materials and resources that present many opportunities not found in a physical classroom

**Science and Maths Tutor** 

International Tutor Group, Vietnam

October 2018 - July 2019

Teaching and developing schemes of work from a variety of curriculums (AQA, Edexcel, OCR etc.).
 Regularly involved outside of the 'classroom'; school events, student's art exhibitions and sports

**English Teacher** 

Wall Street English Vietnam

January 2016 - May 2017

Taught English to adults (many abilities, ages, and group sizes), focusing on practical English.
 Developed weekly up-to-date 'social clubs' based on current affairs, hot topics, and life. Leading

#### Other Positions

**English Teacher** Oct 2014 - November 2015 My English School, Bari, Italy

Practical English. News and Theatre Club

**Factory worker** Sep 2013 - Jan 2014 Promens Packaging, Thetford, UK

Quality control. Working with a team

**Plumbing assistant** Jan 2014 - May 2014 Silenster Building Services, Hockwold, UK

• Client communication. Practical skills

**Shop assistant** Nov 2007 - Sep 2009 Mace Stores, Mundford, UK

Providing friendly service. Organising stock

#### **EDUCATION**

PGCE Secondary Science (spec. Physics with A-Level) University of East Anglia Sep 2017 - July 2018

QTS + NQT passed. Teaching ages 11-18 KS3-5 Science (Biology, Chemistry, and Physics). Supported a very wide range of abilities and needs (e.g. SEND, Pupil Premium, and high attainers). Engaging and varied lessons - assessment strategies, peer teaching, and social learning. Used exciting and safe science demonstrations and experiments to aid my pupil's understanding. Masters-level work analysing research into learning, assessment, and SEND provision (distinction). Implemented strategies of 'Assessment for Learning', differentiation, and collaborative learning

Cambridge CELTA International House Budapest Sep 2014 - Oct 2014

Lesson preparation and delivery for a range of student abilities and lesson types. Creation of a
variety of materials using different sources. Classroom management techniques. Teaching young
people and adults; skills, activities and approaches. Transferable ideas, skills, and practice.
Instruction/Concept Checking Questions, taxonomic questioning, pair discussion, realia.

**BSc (Hons) Natural Sciences, 2.ii** September 2010 - June 2013 University of Durham (Reading: Physics, Classics and Ancient History, and Earth Sciences)

**A-Levels** September 2007 – June 2009 King Edward VI School, Bury St Edmunds

Physics: A Maths: A Chemistry: A Music Technology: B

GCSEs September 2002 – June 2007

Methwold High School, Methwold

English Language: A\* English Literature: A\* Maths: A Science (Double): AA History: A ICT: A Music: B Citizenship: B R.E: B Geography: B Graphics: B German: B

# **VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE, OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS and INFORMATION**

- 2 years weekly maths/science tutoring for GCSE students, with the Durham University SCA
- Classroom assistant at Riverwalk School, Bury for children with learning difficulties
- Active member of the Conservation Society at university
- 3 years Forestry Commission voluntary work litter picking, tree clearing, ticket handling, cafe
- Work at the Centre for Alternative Technology promoting understanding of renewable energy, helping to erect solar panels, working in the allotments
- Regular member of local 'Toadwatch' patrol.
- Piano up to and including Grade 6
- Music Theory Grade 5
- Full UK Driving Licence
- University College Table Tennis captain
- Work on yearly gardening service
- Guitar up to Grade 4
- Methwold High School cricket captain
- Norfolk Junior Badminton champion

#### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

Gardening, gaming, golf, cooking and baking, hiking, playing the piano and guitar, composing and transcribing music, reading, conservation, snooker, travelling, chess

References are available upon request